# Khawar Jatoi

#### Full-Stack Javascript Developer

github.com/khawarjatoi

92 301 776 6650

www.khawarjatoi.com

in linkedin.com/in/khawarjatoi

hey@khawarjatoi.com

Pakistan

#### ABOUT

I've been passionate and committed developer for more than 3 years and have been getting better at programming for most of the time. I may not know all the principles and patterns but I usually know how to find the things I need.

I'm strong in object oriented analysis, design, front-end development with (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and React) as well as back-end development (Node.js, PHP), Relational Databases (MySQL, MariaDB) and Data Query Language (GraphQL).

#### EXPERIENCE

01/2020 - Present

**Full-Stack Javascript Developer** Freelance

- Contract work for web development.
- Mostly working with Javascript ecosystem(React, Node.js)

03/2017 - 12/2019 **Software Engineer** 

Surface Art Engineering, Inc.

Worked as a software engineer and got involved in main project of company.

We spent two years developing a highly complex ERP system and several other projects.

03/2016 - 03/2017 **Desktop Application Developer** Freelance

- Worked as a Desktop Application Developer using C# and developed some applications for small enterprises using MetroFrameworkUi.
- These applications features were to keep track of inventory, customers and client's information, generate invoices, bills and offer sales reports.

#### **EXPERTISE**

WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS3, Javascript, styled-components, React, Redux,

Next.js, React Final Form, Node.js, PHP

**DATABASES** Relational Databases (MySQL, MariaDB, MS SQL Server)

> NoSQL Databases (MongoDB) Data Query Language (GraphQL)

**VERSION CONTROLS** Git, SVN

**OTHER** JWT, OAuth, Prisma Mail Server Setup, Ubuntu,

### **PROJECTS**

Personal Site http://www.khawarjatoi.com  #React #styled-components #Next.js #Heroku	Built personal portfolio to practice React and showcase what I've been working lately.
Ecommerce Website Sample https://bluestarhft.herokuapp.com  Real-Life e-commerce website built with MERN Stack  #React #Redux #React-Final-Form #Next.js #MongoDB #Node.js #Heroku	<ul> <li>An ecommerce website developed using MERN Stack</li> <li>Developed a dashboard with product management capabilities and user authentication.</li> <li>An easy-to-use checkout with discount tools</li> <li>Search and sort to easily find categories</li> <li>Manage categories and sub-categories</li> <li>Feature categories within navigation or on the homepage</li> <li>Search and sort to easily find products in certain categories or with specific attributes</li> </ul>
ERP System  #PHP #Javascript #MySQL #Roundcube #Postfix #Dovecot #Gerbv #PHPSpreadSheet	<ul> <li>Worked with PHP, jQuery and MySQL for storage.</li> <li>Worked on setting up a secure mail server powered by open source technologies like Roundcube, Postfix, and Dovecot. I learned a lot about communication protocols like IMAP or SMTP along the way.</li> <li>Integrated ERP system into Roundcube client.</li> <li>Developed REST APIs and integrated third-party APIs.</li> <li>Worked with open source technologies like gerbv(process Gerber files), PhpSpreadSheet(read and write to spreadsheets), fancyapps(present media) and many more.</li> </ul>
EtherCalc Authentication and Dashboard integration  EtherCalc is a Real-Time open source web spreadsheet.  #LiveScript #Node.js #Express #MongoDB	<ul> <li>I developed few pieces of software on the company scale level.</li> <li>Developed APIs for authentication and data securtiy.</li> <li>Developed dashboard for sheets management.</li> <li>Fixed sheet disappearing and tabs renaming issues in EtherCalc</li> </ul>

## EDUCATION

2015 Masters In Science (MCS)

Institute of Southern Punjab Multan

Computer Science

2018 Self-Learning

Internet

Node.js, Express, React.js, Next.js